Inventory of the Francis Burton Harrison Papers 1786-1932
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Typescripts of Harrison Family Letters, 1786-1889, n.d. (Box-folder 1:1-10)
  - Letters, 1810-1819., 35 items. (Box-folder 1:3-4)
    - William Harrison, Lynchburg, to his father William Harrison, near Williamsburg, 1 May 1817., TCy. (Box-folder 1:4)
    - Ro. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to his uncle Jordan Harrison, Mount Pleasant, Jefferson County, Ohio, 30 September 1818., TCy. (Box-folder 1:4)
    - [?] Lynchburg, to Rob't [? - name and address missing], 26 January 1819., TCy. (Box-folder 1:4)
    - William Harrison, near Mount Pleasant, Ohio, to Samuel J. Harrison, Lynchburg, Virginia, 20 March 1819., TCy. (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Letters, 1820-1829., 12 items. (Box-folder 1:4-5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Richmond, to his son Robert, [no address], 22 October 1820., TCy. (Box-folder 1:4)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to his son Jesse, [no address], 11 November 1821., TCy. (Box-folder 1:4)
    - [Signature missing, but copy noted as in Wm. Harrison's handwriting]. Lynchburg, to his brother Jordan [no address], 25 April 1823., TCy. (Box-folder 1:4)
    - Jordan Harrison, near Mt. Pleasant, to his brother William, Lynchburg, 8 May 1823., TCy. (Box-folder 1:4)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to his son Jesse, [no address], 17 January 1824., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to his son Jesse B. Harrison, Richmond, 14 March 1824., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to his son Jesse, [no address], 30 May 1824., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - William Harrison, Lynchburg, to his brother Jordan Harrison, Mount Pleasant, Ohio, 22 August l825., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Richmond, to Jordan Harrison, Mount Pleasant, Ohio, 22 October 1826., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - Hugh S. Legare, Charleston, South Carolina to J. B. Harrison, Lynchburg, Virginia, 3 November 1828., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to son Jesse B. Harrison, New York, 24 May 1829., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Richmond, to son Jesse [in France?], 25 September 1829., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Letters, 1830-1839., 59 items. (Box-folder 1:5-7)
    - S. J. Harrison, Richmond, to Jesse B. Harrison in Berlin, 13 January 1830., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - [?], Lynchburg, to her brother, Jesse B. Harrison, [no address], 14 May 1830., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to son Jesse, abroad, no address, 27 January 1831., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to son Jesse B. Harrison, New York, 16 May l831., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to Jesse B. Harrison, White Sulphur, 14 August 1831., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Richmond, to Jesse B. Harrison, Lynchburg, 29 September 1831., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Richmond, to Jesse B. Harrison, Lynchburg, 4 October 1831., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to Jesse B. Harrison, New Orleans, 18 December 1831., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to Jesse B. Harrison, New Orleans, 25 December 1831., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to Jesse B. Harrison, New Orleans, 4 February 1832., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to Jesse B. Harrison, New Orleans, 11 March 1832., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to Jesse B. Harrison, New Orleans, 22 April 1832., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to son Jesse, [no address], 1 November 1832., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to Jesse B. Harrison, New Orleans, 11 November 1832., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Richmond, to Jesse B. Harrison, New Orleans, Louisiana, 24 November 1832., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 30 December 1832., TCy. (Box-folder 1:5)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to Jesse B. Harrison, New Orleans, 5 January 1833., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 16 February 1833., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to son Jesse, [no address], 6 April 1833., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to Jesse B. Harrison, New Orleans, 16 June 1833., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, Boxton, 15 August 1833., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, Georgetown, D. C, 15 September 1833., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, Richmond, 29 September 1833., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 1 December 1833., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 14 January 1834., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 16 February 1834., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to John Murrell, [no address], 1 March 1834., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 1 March 1834., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 27 March 1834., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 6 April 1834., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 30 April 1834., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to Jesse Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 22 May 1834., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to Jesse Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 17 December 1834., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, Louisiana, 22 January 1835., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 24 May 1835., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 13 August 1835., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 15 August 1835., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 24 December 1835., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 4 January 1836., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - W. P. H. [William Preston Harrison] Clarksville, to Jesse B. Harrison, New Orleans, 1 February 1836., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 15 August 1836., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - R. J. A. Harrison, Vernon, Madison County, Mississippi to brother, Jesse B. Harrison, New Orleans, 3 November 1836., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - R. J. Harrison near Vernon, Miss. to brother, Jesse B. Harrison, New Orleans, 17 December 1836., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - William [Harrison] Clarksville, to brother, J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 20 December 1836., TCy. (Box-folder 1:6)
    - Wm. P. Harrison, St. Louis, to his brother J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 21 February 1837., TCy. (Box-folder 1:7)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to his son J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 1 March 1837., TCy. (Box-folder 1:7)
    - Wm. [Harrison], St. Louis, to his brother J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 9 April 1837., TCy. (Box-folder 1:7)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to his son J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 22 April 1837., TCy. (Box-folder 1:7)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 13 May 1837., TCy. (Box-folder 1:7)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 1 July 1837., TCy. (Box-folder 1:7)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 7 December 1837., TCy. (Box-folder 1:7)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 27 May 1837., TCy. (Box-folder 1:7)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to Jesse [J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans,] 1 July 1838., 2 copies. TCy. (Box-folder 1:7)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 24 November 1838., TCy. (Box-folder 1:7)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to Jesse [J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans], 20 October 1839., TCy. (Box-folder 1:7)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to Jesse [J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans], 27 October 1839., TCy. (Box-folder 1:7)
    - John A. Harrison, Lynchburg, to "My dear Brother" [Unnamed, but from closing lines, probably to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans], 12 November 1839., TCy. (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Letters, 1840., 5 items. (Box-folder 1:7)
    - M[ary] E. Harrison, Lynchburg, to "my dear Brother" [unnamed, but from last line probably to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans], 29 January 1840., TCy. (Box-folder 1:7)
    - Wm. [Harrison], St. Louis, to "My dear Sister" [Mrs. J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans], 22 April 1840., TCy. (Box-folder 1:7)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, care J. A. Davis, Louisville, Kentucky, 18 May 1840., TCy. (Box-folder 1:7)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to "Dear Jesse" [J. Burton Harrison, then at White Sulphur], 8 July 1840., TCy. (Box-folder 1:7)
    - S. J. Harrison, Lynchburg, to J. Burton Harrison, White Sulphur, 24 August 1840., TCy. (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Letters, 1865-1866. (Box-folder 1:8)
    Letters concerning Burton N. Harrison as prisoner of war.
  - Letter, 1889. (Box-folder 1:9)
    W. S. Bates, Wheeling, to Burton N. Harrison.
  - Letters, n.d. (Box-folder 1:10)
    - Letter addressed to "My Dear Son Samuel", unsigned, but note apparently by Francis Burton Harrison, states "Undated and unsigned - probably Margaret Harrison," n.d., TCy. (Box-folder 1:10)
    - Note of money given William Harrison by his sons, William Jr. and Samuel Jordan, n.d., TCy. (Box-folder 1:10)
  Series 2: Original Manuscripts
- Original Manuscripts, 1825-1839, n.d. (Box-folder 1:11-19)
  - A. Stearns, Cambridge, Massachusetts to Jesse B. Harrison, Lynchburg, Virginia, 2 September 1825. (Box-folder 1:11)
  - John Holt Rice, Theological Seminary, to Reverend Doctor Caldwell, Chapel Hill, North Carolina, 29 April 1826. (Box-folder 1:12)
  - C. Anthony [n.p. - note indicates Lynchburg] to Jesse B. Harrison, n.p., 6 November 1831. (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Tho. R. Ingalls, Jefferson College, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 21 September 1836. (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Enclosed statement says "Memo by Jesse Burton Harrison," 16 November 1836. (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Wm. P. Harrison, St. Louis, to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 20 November 1639. (Box-folder 1:16)
  - S. J. H. [Samuel J. Harrison] to J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 22 February [1839]. (Box-folder 1:17)
  - "E" [Elizabeth Harrison Metcalfe] to brother, J. Burton Harrison, New Orleans, 12 April 1839. (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Memo by the widow of Jesse Burton Harrison [Frances Bland Harrison] for son, Burton N. Harrison, n.d. (Box-folder 1:19)
  Series 3: Notes on Source Materials
- Notes on Source Materials. (Box-folder 2:1-5)
  Notes on source material for The Harrisons of Skimino, and also includes correspondence with Fairfax Harrison.
  Series 4: Miscellaneous Notes and Materials
- Miscellaneous Notes and Materials. (Box-folder 2:6-7)
  - Notes on the Gale Family. (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Papers pertaining to Pocahontas and portraits of Pocahontas. (Box-folder 2:7)